Darshana Welikala

Result-driven professional with well experience in Java/JEE technology stack. A quick learner who has been consistently cited for the ability to adapt to advances in technology with outstanding interpersonal and communication skills.

1194 Westerdam Rd Mississauga, ON L4Y2H4 **(416) 994 - 3412**

{ darshanadev.om { ca.linkedin.com/in/darshanadev} { darshanadev.000webhostapp.com }

EXPERIENCE

TD Bank Group, Canada — IT Solution Developer

DEC 2015 - PRESENT

Playing a web application developer / designer role in TD bank group. Actively involving for MBNA credit card web application development and continuous improvement in cloud environment.

- UI design and implementation using HTML5,CSS3, Javascript/jQuery.
 Use Bootstrap CSS framework to develop responsive user-friendly interfaces
- Middle tier business use cases implementation with Java, Struts2,
 Spring, Web Services in a fast phase (SCRUM) team environment.

CAFE, Canada — Web Developer

IAN 2015 - DEC 2015

Worked as a volunteer web developer for Canadian Association For Equality. Responsible for organization's main website development and maintenance using PHP & Wordpress..

- Designed and implemented cross-platform hybrid-mobile application for the center using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery mobile with phoneGap (cordova).
- Helped and mentor other developers in the team and assisted for centers online campaigns.

GE Transportation, USA — Senior Software Engineer

IAN 2013 - OCT 2014

Senior Developer of an award winning (Green Supply Chain Award) web based comprehensive online "e Logistics control tower solution" that facilitates visibility for crude oil, ethanol and water loads transportation for clients such as Hess,EOG,Noble Energy,ITL, etc in USA.

- Designed and implemented user-friendly GUIs with high performance using SmartGWT javascript framework and HTML5/CSS3 by eliminating the cost of hiring web designers for the project.
- Responsible for middle tier businesses component designing and implementation with Spring, Struts2, Hibernate & Oracle.
- Worked within an highly effective Agile Development (SCRUM) team and achieve the maximum velocity as a self managed team.

EDUCATION

Herzing College, Canada

JAN 2015 - DEC 2015

Diploma in Web Development

University of Colombo, Sri Lanka

DEC 2007 - DEC 2011

Bachelor of Information Technology

SKILLS

Java / JEE

Spring / Spring MVC

Hibernate

MySQL / Oracle 11g

HTML5/CSS3

Bootstrap

Javascripts / JQuery

AngularJS 1.0

JSP/Servlet / Struts 2

RESTFul Services

WebSphere 7 / Tomcat 6

JIRA / BitBucket

SVN / GIT

Jenkins CI

Maven / ANT

Linux user

HIGHLIGHTS

- Best Web Designing Student of the Year Award (3.99 GPA) in Herzing College.
- Oracle Certified Java Programmer for the java Platform 1.5
- MongoDB certified Java Developer

PROJECTS

- To see my **Online portfolio**
- To see my **Side projects**

Please refer my linkedin profile to see my all work experience and educational achievements.